Mohammad Saboori **Software Engineer**

Contact Information:

Email: m.sabouri.soft@gmail.com

Phone: +31 6 28544722

Professional Summary

I am an experienced Software Engineer with a Bachelor's degree in Technical Information and strong skills in Java (versions 5 to 17) and solid experience in SQL databases like Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and MSSQL. I have worked on various projects in banking, insurance, and healthcare sectors, designing and implementing both legacy and modern systems. I'm a Linux enthusiast with a DevOps mindset and enjoy working with back-end and front-end technologies, including Angular. I'm a team player, always ready to learn and collaborate to build efficient solutions.

Skills

Java: Core, EE, Spring, JPA, Apache commons libraries, Junit, Mockito

Arcitecture: Microservices, Monolith, Hexagonal Architecture

DataBase: Oracle Database (PL/SQL), PostgreSQL, MySQL, MSSQL.

Platform; Kafka, Docker, Linux, Azure, AWS, K8s

Tools: Maven, Git, GitLab CI\CD, Jenkins, Tomcat, Jetty, GlasFish, WebLogic, Gradle,

NPM, SonarQube, ArgoCD, HELM, ElasticSearch, UML, SBT, Protobuf

Other Languages: C#, C++, ASP.NET, Scala 2.13

FrontEnd: Angular 11, JSP/JSTL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ext JS (Sencha)

Work Experience

Software Developer ZorgDomein – Health care Sep 2023 - Present

- Developed and maintained the Account backend with Java 17 and spring-boot and tested with Junit.
- Developed and maintained the Transfer healthcare backend application, enhancing patient care using Scala 2.13, Akka HTTP, K8s, and a hexagonal architecture.
- Used Kafka for handling real-time data streams and Protobuf to serialize structured data for Inter-Service communications.
- Dockerized the services and deployed them on AWS, used experimental builds for local testing, and managed the deployments with Argo CD.

- Used the CQRS pattern to separate read and write operations for improved performance and implement logic in the command and query handlers, such as validation, error handling, and interaction with databases.
- Create and optimize complex queries, views, triggers, and stored procedures in PostgreSQL to improve performance.
- Collaborated closely with functional analysts, product designers, and frontend teams, participating in design discussions, conducting code reviews, and coordinating deployment using GitLab CI\CD and modified pipelines by updating the Terraform files.
- Collaborated with DevOps and cross-functional teams for integrations, pipeline modifications, migrations, etc.

Technical Team Lead / Full Stack Developer HCL Technologies - Insurance Jan 2022 - Apr 2023

- Designed, implemented, and maintained a RESTful web application for insurance using Java, Spring Boot framework, and JPA (Java Persistence API), applying the functional programming paradigm within an MVC architecture. Enhanced code quality and maintainability through rigorous analysis with SonarQube.
- Develop and optimize complex SQL queries, stored procedures, functions, and triggers to enhance system performance and perform database administration tasks, including backups, indexing, performance tuning, and security management in MSSQL.
- Manage JavaScript and nodeJS dependencies with NPM.
- Implemented the UI using Angular 11 and RxJS to build a real-time stock market application that handles asynchronous data streams.
- Dockerized the services and deployed them on Azure.
- Create various queries and define the Oracle database objects to enhance efficiency
- Orchestrated deployment using Azure and customized pipelines using YAML files, alongside managing artifacts with Amazon S3.
- Engaged in analysis meetings with end-users, facilitating demos to gather requirements effectively.
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams to integrate various components seamlessly, ensuring robust functionality and user satisfaction.

Senior Java Developer/Technical Team Lead Dotin - Banking Aug 2013 - Oct 2021

- Utilized Java 7 and 8, incorporating Hibernate 3 for object-relational mapping and persistence. Applied object-oriented design principles using the MVC pattern with JSP.
- Utilized tools including Gradle 3.0, Oracle 11, Jenkins, SVN, Git, and deploy application with Tomcat 7.
- participated in analysis sessions with product and domain managers to align technical solutions with business requirements.
- Experienced with NPM to manage nodeJs and JavaScript applications dependencies.

- Worked with large volumes of data, including millions of records, and high transaction rates per second. My experience includes implementing queries for application use or defining views for reporting with high-speed access, normalizing database tables, expanding indexes, and utilizing the features of Oracle 11g database. Additionally, I was responsible for implementing functions and procedures in the database to enhance efficiency.
- Conducted candidate interviews and provided training to new team members and facilitate the user setups providing technical leadership, support, and bug fixing.
- Implemented UI testing using Selenium, Robot framework, and JUnit for robust application testing.
- Collaborated closely with DevOps and cross-functional teams to ensure seamless integration and deployment processes.

Java developer NCG Aug 2011 - Aug 2013

- Developed and maintained ERP web applications, translating user requirements into technical solutions using Java 1.5, the Spring framework, and Oracle database and DWR.
- Implemented functions and procedures in the database to enhance efficiency, integrated them into business logic, and utilized them in calculations, especially for accounting systems.
- Deploy application on Glassfish or WebLogic application server.
- Trained junior team members.

C# .Net Developer Telman Dec 2010 - Apr 2011

- Implemented and maintained features for ERP and MIS systems utilizing C# and ASP.NET.
- Develop and optimize complex queries, stored procedures, functions, and triggers to enhance system performance and perform database administration tasks, including backups, indexing, performance tuning, and security management in MSSQL.

C++ Developer Bahar Sound Dec 2008-Dec 2009

- Implemented new features and maintained a Windows-based learning platform application using C++ (native 98) and OOP design, with MSSQL DB and VOIP standards.
- Design and implement database schemas, tables, views, and stored procedures to support application functionality and manage MSSQL database security, including user roles, permissions, and data encryption to ensure data protection.
- The application facilitated virtual classrooms, allowing teachers to connect with students and providing features such as a blackboard, video conferencing, chat, and more.
- Generated and manually deployed applications to servers via FTP.

Freelance Projects

ViraCam Jun 2018 - Sep 2018

• Analyzed, designed and developed an e-commerce application for a camera WebShop using Java 8, Spring Boot, MySQL, Ionic, and Angular.

Accounting

Jan 2006 - May 2007

• Designed and developed a Windows accounting software system using C# .NET 4.0 and MSSQL database contains sell, buy, employee timesheet, costs, products, various acconting reports.

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology, University of Applied Science and Technology, 2004 - 2008

Languages

English: Full Professional ProficiencyPersian: Native or Bilingual Proficiency